Finding Aid for Mike Wallace papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mike Wallace papers 1956-1963
Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.
9 linear feet
85472 Aa 2
The Mike Wallace papers collection covers Wallace's television and newspaper career in the years 1956 to 1963. Personal and professional correspondence, administrative files, transcripts and outlines of shows, research material, unedited texts of interviews, and other materials related to Night Beat New York Post Column, Newsmaker Productions, Mike Wallace Interview Survival And Freedom Ben Hecht Show WNTA Mike Wallace Interview, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection was the gift of Mr. Wallace (Donor No. 7115) and came to the library on October 22, 1984
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Mike Wallace was born May 9, 1918 in Brookline, Massachusetts the son of Russian Jewish immigrants as Myron Leon Wallace. He graduated from high school in 1935 then attended the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor where he also worked as an announcer at the university radio division. After receiving his degree in 1939 he began his broadcasting career first in Grand Rapids, Mich. at WOOD-WASH radio station, and then at Detroit's WXYZ, where his work included newscasting as well as narration on The Green Hornet. In 1941 he was hired by the Chicago Sun's radio station as a newscaster, but his career was interrupted in 1943 by wartime service in the United States Navy.
In 1946 Wallace was discharged from the service and returned to Chicago. He worked on a variety of interview, news, and entertainment programs. In 1949 he teamed up with his actress-wife, Buff Cobb, in a local radio interview program. In 1951 the pair were put under contract by CBS, moved to New York City, and began a television interview series called Mike and Buff. Marked by frequent staged disagreements between the hosts, the show was a departure from the sugary banter of other husband and wife programs. The show ended in 1954 with the Wallaces' divorce.
Late in 1955 Wallace was hired as news anchor by WABD in New York. In October, 1956 WABD news director Ted Yates replaced the 11 o'clock news with Night Beat. Hosted by Wallace, the hour-long news and interview show featured a darkened set, piercing questions, and the use of prolonged close-ups that gave the show the feel of an interrogation. The sensation created by this show led ABC to pick it up in April, 1957. Renamed The Mike Wallace Interview, it ran only once a week for one-half hour. After losing its sponsor in 1958 the controversial show was picked up for a 19-week run by the Fund for the Republic as Survival and Freedom. Also during these years, Wallace began writing a daily interview column for the New York Post called "Mike Wallace Asks."
After his series at ABC ended in September 1958 Wallace worked briefly with Ted Yates as co-producer of another ABC interview show hosted by author Ben Hecht. In February 1959 Wallace and Yates were hired by New York's WNTA to anchor News Beat, New York's first one-half hour newscast, and to revive The Mike Wallace Interview. Though it ran for two years and was nationally syndicated, it was not as successful as its predecessor.
In the summer of 1960 Wallace also did some work for the Westinghouse Network as co-anchor of its political convention coverage. When he left WNTA, he joined Westinghouse full time as co-host of P.M. East, a talk show which began in June, 1961. In February, 1963 Wallace was hired by CBS News. There he anchored the CBS Morning News, worked as a correspondent, and in 1968 began his ongoing work as one of the reporters of the popular series 60 Minutes. Wallace continued to work on the show until 2006 leading it to the unprecedented rate of 23 seasons on the Nielsen annual top 10 list -- five seasons as the number-one program.
Throughout his career, Wallace has been the recipient of numerous broadcasting awards and honors. Among his prestigious awards are twenty one Emmy Awards, including a prestigious Lifetime Achievement Emmy (2003), the 2002 Fred Friendly First Amendment Award for journalistic contributions to free speech, five DuPont-Columbia Journalism Awards, five John Foster Peabody Awards, the Paul White Award (1991), a Robert E. Sherwood Award, a Robert F. Kennedy Journalism Award grand prize and Television first prize (1996), among others. In June of 1991 he was inducted into the Television Academy Hall of Fame. In 1993 he was named the Broadcaster of the Year by the International Radio and Television Society. Part of his rich legacy includes the Knight-Wallace Fellowship and Mike and Mary Wallace House at the University of Michigan. Wallace's donations support this in-residence study program begun in 1994 for professional journalists seeking to improve their knowledge in a desired field or issue.
Wallace was elected a fellow of the Society of Professional Journalists, Sigma Delta Chi (November 1975) and was awarded a doctorate in humane letters, honoris causa, from the University of Massachusetts (1978). In May 1987 he received an honorary doctorate of laws from the University of Michigan and, in 1989 an honorary doctorate of laws from the University of Pennsylvania.
Mike Wallace died at his home in Canaan, CT on April 7, 2012 at age 93.
The Mike Wallace collection covers Wallace's early television and newspaper work in the years 1956 to 1963. The collection does not yet include materials from his CBS News years, beginning in 1963 and continuing into the 1980s.
Subjects:
Hecht, Ben, 1894-1964.; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.; American newspapers--New York (State)--New York.; Journalists--United States.; Television broadcasting--United States.
Subjects - Photographs:
Hecht, Ben, 1894-1964.; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.; Broadcasting.; Celebrities.; Journalists--United States.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal
  The Personal series includes biographical data, correspondence of a personal or philanthropic nature, texts of speeches, and personal financial information.
  - Biographical (contains vitas and award certificates) (Box 1)
  - Clippings (photocopies of magazine articles about M. Wallace) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1956-1963
    - Rogers and Hammerstein Wing 1961-1962 (Box 1)
      (pertains to Wallace's efforts in the development of cancer center at Hebrew University)
    - Empire State Music Festival 1956-1962 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1961-1963 (Box 1)
      (includes correspondence regarding memorial to deceased son Peter)
  - Speeches undated (Box 1)
    (includes two speeches, one on "controversy in television")
  - Personal financial (Box 1)
- Television and newspaper career 1956-1963
  The Television and Newspaper Career, 1956-1963 series comprises the bulk of the collection. It is arranged chronologically according to program or column. There are eight principal subseries: Night Beat New York Post Column, Newsmaker Productions, Mike Wallace Interview Survival and Freedom Ben Hecht Show WNTA Mike Wallace Interview and Miscellaneous.
  The subseries that deal with television interview programs are arranged similarly. These series begin with administrative or miscellaneous folders containing clippings, fan mail, press releases, and other materials pertaining to that show. The remainder of the folders are then arranged alphabetically by the name of the guest or topic. Each of these alphabetical folders includes a transcript of the show. Many folders also contain research materials on the guest, an assignment sheet, correspondence with guest, and viewer mail.
  The New York Post Column subseries also begins with a miscellaneous folder and is arranged alphabetically according to guest. However, the materials within each folder are different from the television series. Each folder begins with a two or three page sheet called "The Angle,'' outlining the major elements to be covered in the column. This is followed by a series of possible questions, an unedited text of the interview, and several drafts of edited texts. Also included are copies of the actual column, correspondence with the interviewee, and in many cases, research and background material on the interviewee.
  - Index
    - Personal index of interview guests (Box 1)
  - Night Beat (WABD) October 1956-May 1957
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Adams, Joey and Spaeth, Sigmund January 24, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Joey and Stapleton, Maureen April 18, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Adderly, Cannonball and Jayson, Jay April 8, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Adler, Richard and Poling, Daniel Alfred February 12, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Adler, Stella and Javits, Jack October 30, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Dan Dale and Porter, Sylvia F. March 27, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Steve February 15, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Amory, Cleveland and Tsiang, Tingfu March 22, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Bain, Leslie and Kaltenborn, H. V. December 12, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Baldridge, Letitia and Zeckendorf, William November 9, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Barshay, Hyman December 14, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Bean, Orson and Zaharias, George November 28, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Belafonte, Harry and Hart Moss and Carlisle, Kitty October 11, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Belli, Melvin and Schildkraut, Joseph January 22, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Benton, Senator William and Wyler, Gretchen February 13, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Berger, Rabbi, Elmer and Chase, Ilka January 17, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Berkson, Seymour February 14, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Berman, Emile Zola and Maney, Dick February 6, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Bishop, Jim and Russell, Rose V. May 15, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Blanton, Smiley and Roslow, Sydney December 25, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Bowles, Chester December 5, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Browder, Earl February 26, 1957 (see Hvasta, John) (Box 1)
    - Brown, Joe E. and Scheuer, James H. November 27, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Buckley, William F. December 18, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Budge, Don and Morgan, Al January 3, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Cage, John and Ginzburg, Ralph and Taylor, Telford June 3, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Caldwell, Erskine and Gillespie, Dizzy April 9, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Cannon, Jimmy February 5, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Capp, Al and Smith, Shawnee November 23, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Carrington, Elaine and Ritchard, Cyril February 28, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Cassini, Igor and Jurado, Katy October 25, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Cassini, Oleg and Copeland, Jo October 26, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Casting (of actresses) and Shumlin, Herman November 16, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Cerf, Bennett and Levitt, I. M. November 8, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Chapman, John November 2, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Chase, Ilka and Berger, Elmer January 17, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Chester, Hilda (Dodgers fan) and Loeb, Gerald March 8, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Christie, Ernest and Wong, Anna May February 8, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Cohn, Roy and Emery, Stephen October 17, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Coleman, Dr. Lester and Skinner, Cornelia Otis November 22, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Condon, Eddie and Swayze, John Cameron November 13, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Copeland, Jo and Cassini, Oleg October 26, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Cowley, Joyce October 31, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Crowther, Bosley and Weede, Robert April 5, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Currie, Finlay and Korbunski, Stephen and Lloyd, Ruth October 22, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Dali, Salvador and Moore, Cleo December 7, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Dalrymple, Jean and Marshall, Thurgood April 16, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Gary and Kennan, George March 13, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Sammy Jr. and Martin, Pete April 23, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Delaney, Judge Hubert May 5, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Dichter, Dr. Ernest May 1, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Dixon, Sir Pierson April 2, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Dolly, Rosie and Ryan, Patrick J. March 19, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Dube, Harry and Wechsler, James December 13, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Edwards, India and Dixon, Pierson April 3, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Eglevsky, Andre and Robinson, James January 15, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Eliot, Major George and Waters, Ethel December 20, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Emery, Stephen October 17, 1956 (see Cohn, Roy) (Box 1)
    - Ferraday, Lisa and Hurley, Patrick January 4, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Fields, Dorothy and Hefner, Hugh January 9, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Fischer, Dr. Irving and Sims, Sylvia May 23, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Fitch, John and Masters, John May 29, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Foch, Nina and Levin, Meyer February 7, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Ford, Edward Hastings and Jessel, Georgie December 19, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Ford, Eileen and Wolfe, Bertram April 12, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Foreman, Bob and Gazzara, Ben February 19, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Freedman, Dr. Samuel and Janse, Joseph February 20, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Freeman, Mickey and Theodore April 18, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Freuchen, Peter and Kidron, Mordecai January 8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Galento, Tony and Rogers, Don March 20, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Gates, John January 18, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Gazzara, Ben and Foreman, Bob February 19, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Getz, Stan March 28, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Gillespie, Dizzy and Caldwell, Erskine April 9, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Ginzburg, Ralph and Cage, John and Taylor, Telford June 3, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Glass, Joseph and Scarne, John November 15, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Goldstein, Dr. Israel and Louis, Mrs. Joe April 17, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Ghostley, Alice and Kahn, Alexander May 16, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Gould, Morton and Hvasta, John February 27, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Granlund, Nils Thor January 11, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Guggenheimer, Minnie and Sligh, Charles R. May 21, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Halsey, Adm. William and Browder, Earl February 26, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hamid, George and Prelle, Michelline April 10, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hargis, Billy and Colby, Ethel May 3, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Moss and Carlisle, Kitty and Belafonte, Harry October 11, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Justice Walter and Sullivan, Walter March 15, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hartford, Huntington and Lambert, Gerard B. January 23, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hecht, Ben (not Night Beat) (Box 2)
    - Hefner, Hugh and Fields, Dorothy January 9, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Helfand, Julius January 18, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hobson, Laura and Howe, Ronald May 24, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Holiday, Billie November 7, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Hughes, Langston and Ragen, Joseph May 9, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Huie, William Bradford January 16, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hunter, Kim and Pearson, Drew November 14, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Hurley, General Patrick and Ferraday, Lisa January 4, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Hurok, Sol and Levitt, Bill and Chapman, John November 2, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Hvasta, John and Gould, Morton February 27, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Ivy, Dr. Andrew and Talbert, Bill March 14, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Jackson, Mahalia and Pep, Willie February 1, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Janse, Dr. Joseph February 20, 1957 (see Freedman, Samuel) (Box 2)
    - Javits, Jacob and Oboler, Arch and Adler, Stella, October 18 and 30 1956 (Box 2)
    - Jayson, Jay April 8, 1958 (not Night Beat) (Box 2)
    - Jessel, Georgie December 19, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Jones, Carolyn and Rogge, O. John March 26, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Jurado, Katy and Cassini, Igor October 25, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Kahn, Alexander and Ghostley, Alice May 16, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kaltenborn, H. V. December 12, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Kaskel, Clarence January 31, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Walt and Murtagh, John M. January 1, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kennan, George and Davis, Gary March 13, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kiely, Dean Margaret and Parker, Frank March 9, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kidron, Mordecai and Freuchen, Peter January 8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Korbunski, Stephen October 22, 1956 (see Currie, Finlay) (Box 2)
    - Kross, Anna and Bowles, Chester December 5, 1956 (Box 2)
    - LaFarge, Father John and Seldes, Gilbert April 26, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lambert, Gerard and Hartford, Huntington January 23, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lamont, Corliss and Matthews, John March 8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lardner, John and Rathbone, Basil March 1, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lerner, Max and Cowley, Joyce October 31, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Levenson, Sam and Thomas, Norman January 25, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Levitt, Dr. I. M. and Cerf, Bennett November 8, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Levin, Meyer and Foch, Nina February 7, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Levitt, William and Hurok, Sol and Chapman, John November 2, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Lewis, Joseph and Cohen, Alexander May 22, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Ley, Willie October 7, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lilo and Terranova, Peter February 21, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lloyd, Ruth October 22, 1956 (see Currie, Finlay) (Box 2)
    - Loeb, Gerald March 8, 1957 and Berman, Emile Zola and Maney, Dick, February 6, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Logan, Josh and Kinsey, Everett and Patz, Arnall November 1, 1956 (Box 2)
    - London, Ephraim and Arbuthnot, John August 8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lord, Walter and Ford, Art May 10, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Louis, Mrs. Joe and Goldstein, Israel April 17, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Lympany, Moura October 16, 1956 (Box 2)
    - McBride, Mary Margaret and Phillipe, Claude Charles December 4, 1956 (Box 2)
    - McKenna, Siobhan and Newcombe, Don December 11, 1956 (Box 2)
    - MacNamara, Donal E. J. and Williams, Edward Bennett December 27, 1956 (Box 2)
    - McQueen, Butterfly and Buckley, William March 21, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Mailer, Norman and Delaney, Hubert T. March 5, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Marsh, Tiger Joe and Wilson, Donald R. February 6, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Marshall, Thurgood and Dalrymple, Jean April 16, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Martin, Pete and Davis, Jr., Sammy April 23, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Matthews, John and Lamont, Corliss March 8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Maxwell, Elsa and Stout, Rex December 21, 1956 (Box 2)
    - McCafferty, Jeannie and Kirwan, James March 17, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Miller, Rabbi Irving February 5, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Millis, Walter and Von Furstenberg, Betsy October 19, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Moore, Cleo and Dali, Salvador December 7, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Moran, Gussie and Taylor, Gardner April 11, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Morgan, Al and Budge, Don January 3, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Murtagh, John and Kelly, Walt January 1, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Murtagh, John and Cournand, Edouard L. April 29, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Newcombe, Don and McKenna, Siobhan December 11, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Nova, Lou and Lefkowitz, Louis May 22, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Oboler, Arch (see Javitz, Jacob) (Box 3)
    - Parker, Frank March 12, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Pauline, Sam and Stone, I. F. July 18, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Pearson, Drew November 15, 1956 (see Hunter, Kim) (Box 3)
    - Pep, Willie and Jackson, Mahalia February 1, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Phillipe, Claude Charles December 4, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Ploscowe, Judge Morris and Newbigin, J. E. Lesslie August 15, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Poitier, Sidney and Winter, Marjorie January 30, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Polgar, Franz December 18, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Poling, Daniel and Adler, Dick February 12, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Porter, Sylvia and Alexander, Dan Dale March 20, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Powell, Adam Clayton and Emerson, Faye December 26, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Prelle, Michelline and Hamid, George A. April 10, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Preminger, Otto and Bracken, Eddie May 17, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Quill, Mike February 14, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Rathbone, Basil and Lardner, John March 1, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Ragen, Warden Joseph E. and Hughes, Langston May 9, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Reynolds, Earle and Ross, Quitman July 3, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Ritchard, Cyril and Carrington, Elaine February 28, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Robinson, Gladys and Fryschdorf, Channah April 17, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Robinson, Jackie and Granlund, Nils Thor January 11, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Robinson, Rev. James and Eglevsky, Andre and Robinson, Jackie and Granlund, Nils Thor January 15, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Rogers, Don and Galento, Tony March 20, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Rogers, Will Jr. and Beal, John Robinson April 4, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Rogge, O. John and Jones, Carolyn March 26, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Roper, Elmo and Kelly, P. J. May 7, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Roslow, Sydney and Blanton, Smiley December 25, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Ross, Barney and Schoenbrun, David April 19, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Roth, Lillian and Helfand, Julius January 18, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Russell, Rose V. (see Bishop, Jim) (Box 3)
    - Ryan, General Patrick March 19, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Salyer, Ray and Rowan, Carl April 24, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Sayegh, Fayez and White, William S. January 10, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Scarne, John and Glass, Joseph November 15, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Scheuer, James and Brown, Joe E. November 27, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Schildkraut, Joseph and Belli, Melvin January 22, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Schoenbrun, David and Ross, Barney April 19, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Shor, Toots November 29, 1956 (cover sheet only) (Box 3)
    - Shull, Leo and Castle, Eugene April 25, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Shumlin, Herman and Casting of Actresses November 16, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Simpson, Sloan and Walker, Danton October 24, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Skinner, Cornelia Otis and Coleman, Lester November 2, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Slezak, Walter and Hurst, Fannie December 28, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Sligh, Charles R. May 21, 1957 (see Guggenheimer, Minnie) (Box 3)
    - Smith, Shawnee November, 1956 (see Capp, Al) (Box 3)
    - Snyder, Marty January 10, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Sorokin, Pitirim January 31, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund and Adams, Joey January 24, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Stapleton, Maureen and Adams, Joey April 18, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Steuer, Arthur and Logan, Josh November 1, 1956 and Kinsey and Patz (Box 3)
    - Stout, Rex and Zelenko, Herbert June 2, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Stritch, Elaine and Wiley, Tarley Tarson January 29, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Sturges, Preston and Dennis, Lawrence May 14, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Sullivan, Walter and Hart, Walter March 15, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Swayze, John Cameron and Condon, Eddie November 13, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Rev. Gardner and Moran, Gussie April 11, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Telford July 2, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Terranova, Peter and Lilo February 21, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Theodore, Brother and Freeman, Mickey April 18, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Thomas, Norman and Levenson, Sam January 25, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Thorndyke, Dame Sybil and Allen, Steve February 15, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Tsiang, Dr. T. F. (cover sheets) and Amory, Cleveland March 22, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Von Furstenberg, Betsy and Millis, Walter October 19, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Wagner, Bob and Reisel, Victor October 9, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Waters, Ethel and Eliot, George Fielding December 20, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Wayne, David and Barshay, Hyam December 14, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Wechsler, James and Dube, Harry, December 13, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Weede, Robert and Crowther, Bosley April 5, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wertham, Dr. Frederick and Burrows, Abe October 12, 1956 (Box 4)
    - White, William and Sayegh, Fayez January 10, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wiley, Commander T. T. and Stritch, Elaine January 29, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Willis, Richard and Matthews, Herbert L. May 8, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wilson, Donald and Marsh, Tiger Joe February 6, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Winter, Marjorie January 30, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wolfe, Bertram and Ford, Eileen April 12, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wong, Anna May and Christie, Ernest February 8, 1957 (cover sheets) (Box 4)
    - Wright, Martha and Lympany, Moura October 16, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Wyler, Gretchen February 13, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Wylie, Philip May 12, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Zaharias, George November 28, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Zeckendorf, William November 9, 1956 (Box 4)
  - New York Post Column, September 1957-August 1958
    - Miscellaneous (includes chronological index of column guests and promotional material) (Box 4)
    - Booklet of notable columns (Box 4)
    - Interviews
      - Adams, Joey November 29, 1957 (Box 4)
      - Adler, Charles, unused April, 1958 (Box 4)
      - Adler, Stella, unused November, 1958 (Box 4)
      - Allen, Robert, unused February, 1958 (Box 4)
      - American dog November 5, 1957 (Box 4)
      - American driver May 29, 1958 (Box 4)
      - Amory, Cleveland September 19, 1957 (Box 4)
      - Amin, Mustafa (Nasser) April 22, 1958 (Box 4)